<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mpdreamz.nl</title>
    <atom:link href="//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>-Love data, design and most of all, the web</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
    <generator>The mighty Wintersmith</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <item>
      <title>Getting my blog on</title>
      <link>//articles/getting-my-blog-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">//articles/getting-my-blog-on/</guid>
      <author></author>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I started to blog, lets see how long I keep this up.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like most developers getting my blog up and running started to become the end goal instead of an ends to a means to get my so called words of wisdom on the internet.
So I&apos;m putting this up, wards and all, frankly who gives a damn (yet).

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last time I tried to set up a blog I checked out Octopress and fell into the same trap: playing with code is alot easier then to actually blog. &quot;Oh hey this is made with ruby, let&apos;s redo &lt;a href=&quot;http://rubykoans.com/&quot;&gt;ruby-koans&lt;/a&gt; and get reacquainted with the language&quot;. So this time I started looking for node based static site generators. as I know that ecosystem a whole lot better. Only to get sidetracked with the intricacies of the static site generator I ended up choosing: &lt;a href=&quot;http://jnordberg.github.com/wintersmith/&quot;&gt;wintersmith&lt;/a&gt;. 

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next thing to lure me away from actually writing a damn blog post was where to host it. 

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first thought was github pages but that would mean generating the site and copying it to &lt;code&gt;gh-pages&lt;/code&gt; branch commit/push and switch back. 
This didn&apos;t sound like an ideal work flow.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My second thought was hosting it on Azure, I&apos;ve recently used it to deploy &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.studioquestionmark.nl&quot;&gt;a site for a friend&lt;/a&gt; and was suprised with how painless that was to setup. I&apos;d just run the blog programmatically, tad wasteful but again who gives a damn wheter this blog is static or served from &lt;code&gt;server.js&lt;/code&gt;.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then found &lt;a href=&quot;http://tlvince.com/wintersmith-on-heroku&quot;&gt;this excellent blog post&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://tlvince.com/about&quot;&gt;Tom Vincent&lt;/a&gt; detailing how to do it on heroku,
the right way... static. 

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly I couldn&apos;t quite get his build on heroku itself to work and just check in my build output, but overall I&apos;m happy with the current setup.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some quick first observations on heroku itself

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feels slower then azure,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the command line is incredible but also confusing, the help mentions &lt;code&gt;run:console [Command]&lt;/code&gt; but the actual command is &lt;code&gt;run console [Command]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stuff like &lt;code&gt;heroku logs&lt;/code&gt; is awesome, &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;error messages like &apos;Error H14 (No web processes running)` are not idiot (read: me) proof. In hindsight issueing &apos;heroku ps:scale web=1&apos; seems totally obvious.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the ease of getting a node app online Azure felt alot easier. I&apos;m not drawing any conclusion from my 30 minute exposure to heroku though.

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up on my blog procastination list: fix the VIM markdown highlighter which barfs on quotes.







&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>